<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>CT-Technologies</title>
    <link href="https://www.ct-technologies.dk/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
    <link href="https://www.ct-technologies.dk"/>
    <updated>2023-11-08T11:46:18+07:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>General Editors</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.ct-technologies.dk</id>

    <entry>
        <title>A Professional Network</title>
        <author>
            <name>General Editors</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.ct-technologies.dk/a-professional-network-of-cold-storage-industry/"/>
        <id>https://www.ct-technologies.dk/a-professional-network-of-cold-storage-industry/</id>
            <category term="News"/>

        <updated>2023-11-03T10:31:57+07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Cold storage industry architects and engineers benefit from new Women in CEBA program. Almedina Hamzić Mušić, Assistant Design Manager at CT-Technologies, challenges stereotypes in the male-dominated construction industry. (Photo courtesy of Almedina Hamzić Mušić.) Empowering. Barrier-breaking. These are some of the terms women in the&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                
    <blockquote class="blockquote">
      Cold storage industry architects and engineers benefit from new Women in CEBA program.
    </blockquote>

    <figure class="post__image post__image--wide">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/30/Picture1.jpg" height="644" width="990" alt="Image of Almedina Hamzić Mušić, Assistant Design Manager at CT-Technologies, challenges stereotypes in the male-dominated construction industry."  sizes="100vw" srcset="https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/30/responsive/Picture1-xs.jpg 300w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/30/responsive/Picture1-sm.jpg 480w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/30/responsive/Picture1-md.jpg 768w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/30/responsive/Picture1-lg.jpg 1024w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/30/responsive/Picture1-xl.jpg 1360w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/30/responsive/Picture1-2xl.jpg 1600w">
      <figcaption>Almedina Hamzić Mušić, Assistant Design Manager at CT-Technologies, challenges stereotypes in the male-dominated construction industry. (Photo courtesy of Almedina Hamzić Mušić.)</figcaption>
    </figure>

  <p>
    <b>Empowering. Barrier-breaking. These are some of the terms women in the controlled environment building industry use to describe the new “Women in CEBA” program from the Global Cold Chain Alliance (GCCA). Women in CEBA provides a support network for women in the male-dominated field. (CEBA (Cold Environment Building Association) is a cold chain partner of GCCA.)</b>
  </p>

  <p>
    “Being part of Women in CEBA is a naturally empowering experience to me, and I see it as an opportunity to challenge the stereotype of construction being a male-dominated industry,” says Almedina Hamzić Mušić, Assistant Design Manager at CT-TECHNOLOGIES in Sarajevo, Bosnia and Herzegovina.
  </p>

  <p>
    Kristin Westover, Technical Manager, Specialty Installations with GAF, echoes Mušić’s sentiment. “We are breaking barriers in the industry,” she comments. “It is great to know that we have a group of smart, high performing and high-achieving women, and we are all in this together. We can uplift each other and do great things within the industry.”
  </p>

  <p>
    Mušić and Westover joined a third member of Women in CEBA, Kate Lyle of Ware Malcomb, to discuss their roles in the industry, their motivations to stay in the cold storage industry and the need for the Women in CEBA program.
  </p>

  <p>
    Choosing Cold Storage The architects and engineers uniformly say the unique complexity of cold storage is most appealing. A licensed architect, Lyle oversees the Ware Malcomb national practice focused on cold storage, food and beverage processing and food-grade buildings. She joined the firm after working on mostly speculative industrial buildings for about six years.
  </p>

  <p>
    That was 2019. It was a good move, she says. “I found it fascinating! From an architectural standpoint, there’s so much complexity and detail. And I also really enjoyed learning about the food supply chain, and all the buildings that help move and process food from farm to table,” Lyle says.
  </p>

  <p>
    “When I joined Ware Malcomb, I was looking for an opportunity to really grow my career, and they said that I would have room to grow,” Lyle recalls. “I’ve been very pleased to find that to be the case.” She started as senior project architect and has been promoted twice, to studio manager, industrial cold and food in 2020 and to her current role as director, industrial cold and food in 2021.
  </p>

  <p>
    Taking a different path, Mušić says she “always had an interest in industrial architecture and practical solutions that have a significant impact on preserving perishable goods. The cold chain industry, with its critical role in this aspect, captured my attention.” Mušić entered the cold storage industry in 2020, not long after completion of her master’s degree in architecture and urban planning. She had previously worked in residential and commercial construction as well as in industrial heritage.
  </p>

  <p>
    At CT-TECHNOLOGIES, Mušić says the greatest challenge has been ensuring successful project execution in demanding environments such as in Southeast Asia and Africa. “These regions present unique logistical and climatic complexities that require innovative solutions and great adaptability to meet tight schedules and achieve the seamless construction of cold storage facilities,” she says.
  </p>

  <p>
    A professional engineer, Westover joined GAF in 2020 from a structural engineering consultancy where her work focused on existing buildings. She also performed thirdparty inspections for various building envelope systems in new construction projects.“Every building is different,” she observes. “I loved the technical aspect of understanding how building parts come together to make a high-performing building.”
  </p>

  <p>
    At GAF, Westover specializes in cold storage roofing assemblies, bringing her past design experience into the manufacturing world and working with designers and consultants to optimize roofing assemblies.
  </p>

  <p>
    “Cold storage buildings, while they are the same roof assemblies as ‘regular’ buildings, require special details to ensure that the roof functions properly, including keeping the inside cold,” Westover explains. “Working in the field of cold storage has allowed me to use my knowledge of high-performing buildings and technical detailing to translate into the best roofing assemblies for our cold storage customers.”
  </p>

    <h2 id="a-day-in-the-life">
      A Day in the Life
    </h2>

  <p>
    All three of the Women in CEBA members say no two days are the same.
  </p>

  <p>
    Westover consults with designers and contractors on ongoing cold storage roof projects, including on the constraints of projects in the design phase, to help them decide the best roof assembly for their project and to ensure the roof is energy efficient and airtight. “I consider each of our projects a team effort,” Westover explains. “Keeping open lines of communication and contact ensures that we are going to have the most high-performing roofing system for each cold storage facility.”
  </p>

  <p>
    Westover also visits worksites to check on progress and help troubleshoot any problems. “That is the fun part of construction,” she says. “You can always anticipate something you didn’t anticipate.”
  </p>

  <p>
    An expert on cold storage roofing, Westover often shares her knowledge in lunch-and-learn presentations for designers and contractors and travels to conferences to stay educated on topics within the building industry.
  </p>

  <p>
    Like Westover, Mušić works closely with the design team, conducting design reviews, collaborating with architects and engineers, and ensuring that the design plans meet client requirements and industry standards. She participates in client meetings to address design-related queries and incorporates their feedback into the project.
  </p>

  <p>
    “Throughout the day, I’m involved in project coordination, managing timelines and liaising with various stakeholders to ensure smooth project execution. Certainly, each day presents its own set of challenges and opportunities for growth, making my work both diverse and fulfilling,” Mušić says.
  </p>

  <p>
    As the leader of a small team of specialists, Lyle explains, “My days vary a lot, but at the heart of it is sharing my knowledge about cold storage and industrial food design, both internally and with our clients and consultants.”
  </p>

  <p>
    Some days that means meeting with clients about new projects and responding to RFPs, while other days, she interfaces with local Ware Malcomb offices to help with projects. She might develop training programs for her company colleagues on key components in cold storage design. Or she might help a project manager modify a detail to meet local code requirements. She also performs quality control reviews to ensure plans address all of the nuances of cold or food design.&nbsp;
  </p>

    <h2 id="gender-parity">
      Gender Parity
    </h2>

  <p>
    On the need for the Women in CEBA program, the three women share their experiences in predominantly male professions.
  </p>

  <p>
    Lyle, who recalls that half of the students in her architecture program were women, says she was surprised when the gender ratio was different in her first job. “I was the only woman. My engineering consultants were men, my contractors were men, the developers were men. It was so surprising to me,” Lyle says. “It has slowly gotten better. I work with many more women both at Ware Malcomb, and amongst our clients and consultants. But while I’m no longer the only woman, we’re still a long way from 50/50.”
  </p>

  <p>
    Westover agrees. Although she says construction overall, including in the cold storage industry, is predominantly a male industry, she welcomes the increasing number of women. “I definitely have seen an increase in the number of women in the industry in the 15 years I have been working in it.”
  </p>

  <p>
    Indeed, gender parity has improved some over time, but that progress has been very slow. Only 15% of engineering positions were held by women in 2020 across six Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD) countries – Australia, Brazil, Canada, India, United Kingdom and the United States. In contrast, 39% of all jobs were held by women in these countries, according to the World Economic Forum Global Gender Gap Report 2022.
  </p>

  <p>
    “I am optimistic that these issues will continue to evolve positively in the coming years,” Mušić says. “In my experience as someone involved in the academic world, I have observed a notable increase in female representation across various engineering fields, which is an encouraging trend.”
  </p>

  <p>
    “Diversity leads to better design,” says Lyle. “Every person in the design-build community brings a wealth of knowledge from our lives and experiences, and the greater the variety of those experiences, the better the buildings. I hope more women will join the industry, and stay in the industry and be valued for the diverse experiences they can bring to the table.”
  </p>

    <h2 id="looking-to-the-future">
      Looking to the Future
    </h2>

  <p>
    Although women occupy more science and technology roles today, including in the cold storage industry, there are signs that future progress will require a concerted effort. Women remain significantly underrepresented in engineering, manufacturing and construction classrooms, affecting the future pipeline for women in these roles.
  </p>

  <p>
    In the United States, almost half of students pursuing an architectural degree today are women, according to the American Institute of Architects (AIA), yet only a small proportion ultimately become registered architects. Fewer than one in five (17%) registered architects are women in the United States, according to AIA.
  </p>

  <p>
    “I think each sector of the industry has its own challenges, but on the architecture side I think the biggest problem is attrition,” Lyle explains. “Women are still graduating as architects, but they are leaving the industry for a wide variety of reasons, and so it’s a very complex problem to solve.”
  </p>
<hr class="separator separator--dots" />

  <p>
    Source: Cold Facts Magazine September – October 2023. Page 16 -17. A Professional Network Cold storage industry architects and engineers benefit from new Women in CEBA program by Gina Veazey.<br><a href="https://www.gcca.org/magazine-article/cold-facts-september-october-2023/" target="_blank">https://www.gcca.org/magazine-article/cold-facts-september-october-2023/</a><br>
  </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Building Cold Chain In Africa</title>
        <author>
            <name>General Editors</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.ct-technologies.dk/building-cold-chain-in-africa/"/>
        <id>https://www.ct-technologies.dk/building-cold-chain-in-africa/</id>
            <category term="News"/>

        <updated>2023-11-08T11:46:18+07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    On average, 50% of the food produced in African countries is wasted – an amount that could feed 300 million people. According to the Food and Agricultural Organization of the United Nations (FAO), this is mainly a result of the inefficient supply chain infrastructure within&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                
  <p>
    On average, 50% of the food produced in African countries is wasted – an amount that could feed 300 million people. According to the Food and Agricultural Organization of the United Nations (FAO), this is mainly a result of the inefficient supply chain infrastructure within the agricultural sector where in sub-Saharan Africa alone, more than 60% of the population are smallholder farmers.
  </p>

  <p>
    “The benefits of temperature control and maintenance of the cold chain are often seen as nonessential and a luxury in different parts of Africa,” explains Gary Benatar, CEO of Relog, a design/build firm headquartered in Cape Town, South Africa. “Building a temperature-controlled warehouse or distribution center is just the first part – you have to look at the complete supply chain, including transportation and the retail environment.” Benatar notes that often African consumers do not have a refrigerator in their home, and food is purchased in quantities for immediate consumption. “This also means the long-term shelf life that we value in products is irrelevant in these markets,” Benatar says. “Our customers are not ready yet,” says James Eason, who worked in Africa for years and is a cold chain technical advisor to GCCA. “Food production is almost nonexistent, logistical costs will never go down, not to mention the infrastructure issues.” Eason believes the number one factor companies looking to build or operate temperature-controlled warehouses in Africa need to understand is that the fundamentals on which the 3PL model is based – infrastructure and logistical systems, the water and sewer systems – are all substandard.
  </p>

    <h2 id="energy-and-other-constraints">
      Energy and Other Constraints
    </h2>

  <p>
    In most African countries, electricity costs are very high and outages are common, especially in remote farming areas, says Carsten Thorsen, CEO, CT-TECHNOLOGIES, a Danish design/build company that has been operating in Africa for nearly 20 years. “Having a cold storage facility without a back-up electrical solution is sometimes a challenge,” Thorsen says. “At the same time, many builders without cold storage experience are constructing facilities with inappropriate materials. This leads to huge energy consumption, which further demotivates the use of temperature-controlled warehouses.” Apart from changing from freon units to ammonia systems, Thorsen said many operators are now choosing 200 mm PIR insulation rather than 150 mm as they had before. He notes solar power is discussed but has not yet broken though. “Using solar panels to produce electricity could be a solution, especially if the country’s grid system can take the extra energy produced during the day to be used during the night – a net metering system,” Thorsen says. Many cold stores used to be refrigerated by several split units with freon, but now many users are moving to central ammonia systems, which offer 30 to 40% savings on electricity, Thorsen explains. “This means a lot in Nigeria, for example, where the public power supply is very unreliable, and the plants are running on diesel generators most of the time.”
  </p>

    <h2 id="building-and-costs">
      Building and Costs
    </h2>

  <p>
    “To start with, I highly recommended using the appropriate material in construction that can save and maintain the temperature inside the facilities for some time when the electricity is out,” says Thorsen. He adds that today, goods in warehouses in most African countries are traditionally stacked on the floor. “Room height used to be 6 meters (20 feet) but now I also see 8 meters (26 feet) – racking is rarely considered.” When it comes to cost, Thorsen explains building materials and spare parts are still not available in most of African countries, which leads to high prices because of importing these materials.
  </p>

  <p>
    “Most of the technology and skills are imported, as there are limited local resources outside of South Africa” Benatar says. “And the high cost of the imported building materials is exacerbated by high import duties and government bureaucracy, which adds to costs, delays and difficulty developing worldclass facilities.” “In Africa, because of energy and inadequate transport infrastructures, you need self-sufficient, small, prefabricated facilities at production/recollection zones, which normally are far apart from consumption and export areas,” says Manuel Cabrera, Executive Managing Director, Technical Operations for Ifria, an integrated cold chain development company in North and West African markets.
  </p>

  <p>
    “In consumption zones, more traditional cold facilities are required in order to combine import/export, distribution and other cold storage services to optimize these facilities.” Cabrera says African markets need robust capable facilities and logistics built to modern standards but not overdesigned nor over automated as the market simply isn’t there yet. “There are needs everywhere but it is important to stay focused on serving demand and that is HRI (hotel restaurant institutional) and modern grocery retail and bulk commodity storage for leading agri-producers,” says Cabrera. “Facility design should include robust and modern facilities and logistics offering value added services, notably pre-cooling, which is almost absent from the African market and necessary to unlock export potential.”
  </p>

    <h2 id="last-milefirst-mile">
      Last Mile/First Mile
    </h2>

  <p>
    With the increase in online shopping resulting from the pandemic, Benatar says there has been an enormous increase in scooters and other smaller vehicles making last mile deliveries in cities in South Africa and other countries. “However, the maintenance of the cold chain in the last mile is poor with no refrigeration, sometimes some insulation and the addition of dry ice (or eutectic plates), but that is the exception rather than the rule,” he says. “Last mile is really hard for distribution purposes,” says Cabrera. “Besides consumer purchasing behavior and low cold chain culture, you have to deal with traffic volumes, restrictions and regulations, downtown tonnage restrictions, delivery time windows and noise regulations.”
  </p>

  <p>
    Cabrera says when it comes to first mile origin, there is inefficient or almost no cold storage infrastructure, package houses and post-harvest facilities, and up to 50% of foodstuffs are lost. “As a result, farmers have to sell at much lower prices, food quality is worse and has a lower commercial life span,” he notes. “First mile cold chain infrastructure is one of the best investments for developing countries as it increases domestic production with higher standards, produces more consistent foodstuffs with longer shelf life, and those countries can substitute imports with domestic production and even export, should the products meet consumer requirements.” “With respect to first mile delivery, in most cases this is better controlled by the manufacturer and retailer in a formal market, and most reputable manufacturers with brands to manage will control the cold chain if necessary,” Benatar explains. “However, in informal markets and with informal farmers, the route to market and the control of the cold chain is poor. There is a drive to improve this in most of Africa, and an opportunity exists.” Thorsen says while the lack of a cold chain makes first mile practices to extend the life of perishable products challenging and not very common, this is slowly starting to change with the help of visionary entrepreneurs.
  </p>

    <figure class="post__image post__image--wide">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/29/Picture1.jpg" height="227" width="752" alt="Image of Warehouse construction underway in Ghana for Trust Link Ventures Limited, a fish import/resale trading company that currently runs its operations from rented facilities."  sizes="100vw" srcset="https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/29/responsive/Picture1-xs.jpg 300w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/29/responsive/Picture1-sm.jpg 480w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/29/responsive/Picture1-md.jpg 768w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/29/responsive/Picture1-lg.jpg 1024w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/29/responsive/Picture1-xl.jpg 1360w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/29/responsive/Picture1-2xl.jpg 1600w">
      <figcaption>Warehouse construction underway in Ghana for Trust Link Ventures Limited, a fish import/resale trading company that currently runs its operations from rented facilities.</figcaption>
    </figure>

    <h2 id="the-visionaries">
      The Visionaries
    </h2>

  <p>
    “Our vision is an interactive cold chain from first mile to end customer that is built with international expertise to the highest industry standards for cold storage to ensure compliance with international certifications,” says Matthew Meredith, Executive Managing Director, Operations at Ifria. “However, this does not necessarily mean the assets need to be very expensive. Facilities must be robust and not overengineered, with a simple and efficient operational layout.”
  </p>

  <p>
    Matthew says Ifria has two integrated cold chain solutions. The first are cold hubs – more sophisticated assets designed for airports, maritime ports or agri-business industrial zones. The hubs offer efficient renewable energy integration with phase I capacity for 5,000 pallets and direct cross-docking and other value-added services related to cold storage. The Phase I design integrates planned expansions. The second integrated cold chain solution is a first-mile network of on-farm, remotely monitored, post-harvest modular cold storage units capable of hold 1000 tons or 1000 to 2000 tonnes, and available to growers as needed. Ifria accomplishes this through partnerships with first mile producers. “We develop with ecosystem partners, programs intended for grant support that focus on an innovative business model that brings smaller-scale cold chain assets into an integrated model,” says Meredith. “I’m optimistic about building the cold chain in Africa. The need is here, there is a willingness to pay, we’ve done it before, and we have the people who know how to build a cold chain in emerging markets with capital and development partners who are willing to support this growth.”&nbsp;
  </p>

    <figure class="post__image post__image--wide">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/29/Picture3.jpg" height="352" width="752" alt="Image of We2 Fisheries in Ghana."  sizes="100vw" srcset="https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/29/responsive/Picture3-xs.jpg 300w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/29/responsive/Picture3-sm.jpg 480w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/29/responsive/Picture3-md.jpg 768w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/29/responsive/Picture3-lg.jpg 1024w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/29/responsive/Picture3-xl.jpg 1360w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/29/responsive/Picture3-2xl.jpg 1600w">
      <figcaption>We2 Fisheries in Ghana.</figcaption>
    </figure>

    <h2 id="growing-interest">
      Growing Interest
    </h2>

  <p>
    The interest in Africa in building temperaturecontrolled warehouses for horticultural needs is growing, according to Thorsen. “Some farmers are more interested in showing the quality of their products to exporters, while others want to reduce the waste and product loss, but overall, there is still a big need for solutions.” Thorsen adds, “There is a future vision of Africa becoming the center of agriculture – the tropical fruits are the best quality in the world and of interest to many investors looking to establish cold chains to reduce the considerable loss of fresh fruit and vegetables. With more awareness and investment, the future looks promising in having more temperature-controlled facilities accommodating different products.”
  </p>

  <p>
    As for frozen food cold storage, Thorsen believes the demand is stable for now but will be expected to increase as cold chains improve. Benatar agrees there is increased interest in building temperature-controlled warehouses in Africa. “There are some special funding opportunities through the World Bank and developers are seeing this as an opportunity,” he says. “As the density of cities grows and the traffic congestion increases, the move to more formal trading will increase and so will the requirement for cold chain infrastructure,” Benatar says.
  </p>

  <p>
    “The pandemic and vaccines have also increased this requirement.” Benatar believes the cold chain in Africa will continue to grow as supply chains get longer and more controls are put in place to ensure better quality and freshness for consumers. “Eventually, these countries will legislate food safety,” he says. Meredith notes cold chain studies conducted by Ifria indicate as markets move from “informal” (currently 80%) to “formal” structures, food hygiene regulations increase, driving up demand for cold chain. Also, major international food retailers are expanding in the region which is driving food value chains to improve quality and services. Meredith says this elevates the quality of the entire market. “Building the cold chain in Africa creates business opportunities along the supply chain, starting from the smallholder farmer to the sophisticated retailer,” says Meredith. “At the end of the day, an interconnected African cold chain can deliver profitable investment returns linked to broad-based impact and will help achieve a better standard of living in Africa.”
  </p>
<hr class="separator separator--dots" />

  <p>
    Source: Cold Facts Magazine September – October 2021. Page 14 -18. Building the Cold Chain in Africa by Alexandra Walsh.<br><a href="https://www.gcca.org/magazine-article/building-cold-chain-africa/" target="_blank">https://www.gcca.org/magazine-article/building-cold-chain-africa/</a><br>
  </p>

  <p>
    
  </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Sandwich Panel for Construction Materials</title>
        <author>
            <name>General Editors</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.ct-technologies.dk/sandwich-panel-for-construction-materials/"/>
        <id>https://www.ct-technologies.dk/sandwich-panel-for-construction-materials/</id>
            <category term="News"/>

        <updated>2023-10-23T16:50:01+07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Sandwich panels are a wide-spread construction material that has rapidly gained popularity across various industries. They are made by joining two layers of material (usually metal, wood, or plastic) with a core material in between. Sandwich panels are known for their exceptional strength, insulation properties,&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                
  <p>
    Sandwich panels are a wide-spread construction material that has rapidly gained popularity across various industries. They are made by joining two layers of material (usually metal, wood, or plastic) with a core material in between. Sandwich panels are known for their exceptional strength, insulation properties, and ease of installation. CT-TECHNOLOGIES will explore what sandwich panels are, how to properly utilise them in construction and on projects, review different types available, technical specifications, and underline numerous advantages of using sandwich panels in construction and beyond.
  </p>

    <h2 id="what-are-sandwich-panels">
      What are Sandwich Panels?
    </h2>

  <p>
    Sandwich panels consist of three main components: two outer layers, known as face panels or face sheets, and a core material sandwiched between them. The outer layers are typically made of materials like steel, aluminium, wood, or fibre-reinforced plastic, and the core material can be constructed from various substances, such as polyisocyanurate or polyurethane foam, mineral wool, expanded polystyrene (EPS) or aluminium honeycomb. The combination of these materials creates a composite structure that exhibits exceptional structural properties, thermal insulation, and acoustical performance.<br>
  </p>

    <h2 id="types-of-sandwich-panels">
      Types of Sandwich Panels
    </h2>

  <p>
    Sandwich panels are widely used in construction and other applications for their thermal insulation, structural properties and installation speed. The choice of core material can significantly impact the panel's performance. Here's an explanation of the four types of most common core materials: PIR, PUR, Quadcore, and Mineral Wool.
  </p>

  <p>
    <b>1. PIR (Polyisocyanurate) Core Panels:</b>
  </p>

    <figure class="post__image post__image--center">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/28/Picture1.jpg" height="80" width="207" alt="PIR (Polyisocyanurate) Core Panels"  sizes="100vw" srcset="https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/28/responsive/Picture1-xs.jpg 300w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/28/responsive/Picture1-sm.jpg 480w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/28/responsive/Picture1-md.jpg 768w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/28/responsive/Picture1-lg.jpg 1024w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/28/responsive/Picture1-xl.jpg 1360w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/28/responsive/Picture1-2xl.jpg 1600w">
      
    </figure>

  <p class="indent-sm-start-3">
    PIR is a thermosetting plastic and foam insulation material. PIR core panels are a type of rigid foam insulation. They have a closed-cell structure, which means the gas trapped within the cells does not dissipate, providing excellent thermal resistance.<br><br><b>Advantages:</b> PIR panels offer high thermal performance and good fire resistance, and they are lightweight. They are used in cold storage, temperature controlled facilities, clean rooms, data centres and other types of construction where high insulation levels are required.
  </p>

  <p>
    <span style="font-family: var(--editor-font-family); font-size: 1em; background-color: ; font-style: ; font-variant-ligatures: ; font-variant-caps: ;"><b>2. PUR (Polyurethane) Core Panels:</b></span>
  </p>

    <figure class="post__image post__image--center">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/28/Picture2.jpg" height="92" width="200" alt="PUR (Polyurethane) Core Panels"  sizes="100vw" srcset="https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/28/responsive/Picture2-xs.jpg 300w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/28/responsive/Picture2-sm.jpg 480w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/28/responsive/Picture2-md.jpg 768w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/28/responsive/Picture2-lg.jpg 1024w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/28/responsive/Picture2-xl.jpg 1360w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/28/responsive/Picture2-2xl.jpg 1600w">
      
    </figure>

  <p class="indent-sm-start-3">
    PUR is another type of rigid foam insulation, similar to PIR. The difference between PUR and PIR is the ratio of Polyol to Isocyanate. PIR has a higher ratio of Isocyanate which improves the fire performance of the panel. PUR is easier to manufacture than PIR.<br><b style="font-family: var(--editor-font-family); font-size: 1em; background-color: ; font-style: ; font-variant-ligatures: ; font-variant-caps: ;"><br>Advantages:</b><span style="color: var(--text-primary-color); font-family: var(--editor-font-family); font-size: 1em; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);"> PUR panels are known for their good insulation properties, and they are versatile in various applications. They are commonly used in roofing and wall applications in commercial and industrial buildings. However, this type of core is slowly becoming obsolete and is being replaced in market by more advanced Quadcore and PIR cores.</span>
  </p>

  <p>
    <b>3. Quadcore Panels:</b>
  </p>

    <figure class="post__image post__image--center">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/28/Picture3.jpg" height="109" width="191" alt="Quadcore Panels"  sizes="100vw" srcset="https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/28/responsive/Picture3-xs.jpg 300w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/28/responsive/Picture3-sm.jpg 480w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/28/responsive/Picture3-md.jpg 768w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/28/responsive/Picture3-lg.jpg 1024w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/28/responsive/Picture3-xl.jpg 1360w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/28/responsive/Picture3-2xl.jpg 1600w">
      
    </figure>

  <p class="indent-sm-start-3">
    Quadcore is a brand name for a type of insulated metal panel with a unique core structure. It incorporates the qualities of PIR and PUR foam, providing a balance between thermal performance, fire resistance, and structural strength.<br><br><b>Advantages:</b> Quadcore panels offer improved thermal efficiency and better fire performance compared to traditional PUR or PIR panels. Similar to PIR core panels, they are being used primarily in cold store industry where they offer either increased thermal characteristics or same thermal characteristics with reduced panel thickness in comparison with PIR counterpart panels.
  </p>

  <p>
    <b>4. Mineral Wool Core Panels:</b>
  </p>

    <figure class="post__image post__image--center">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/28/Picture4.jpg" height="109" width="156" alt="Mineral Wool Core Panels"  sizes="100vw" srcset="https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/28/responsive/Picture4-xs.jpg 300w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/28/responsive/Picture4-sm.jpg 480w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/28/responsive/Picture4-md.jpg 768w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/28/responsive/Picture4-lg.jpg 1024w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/28/responsive/Picture4-xl.jpg 1360w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/28/responsive/Picture4-2xl.jpg 1600w">
      
    </figure>

  <p class="indent-sm-start-3">
    Mineral wool is a non-metallic, inorganic insulation material made from natural minerals and recycled materials. It has a fibrous structure that provides good thermal insulation and acoustic properties.<br><br><b>Advantages:</b> Mineral wool core panels are known for their excellent fire resistance and good sound insulation. Mineral wool does not burn but will melt when temperatures reach beyond 1,800°F (1,000°C). The insulation performs as a fire barrier and can used in sandwich panels provide fire resistance of more than 4 hours. They are commonly used in applications where fire safety and acoustic performance are essential, such as industrial buildings and residential construction. Disadvantage is mineral wool absorbs moisture if not covered by vapor barrier.&nbsp;<br>
  </p>

  <p>
    Choosing the appropriate core material depends on the specific requirements of your project. PIR and PUR panels are preferred for their thermal performance, while Quadcore offers a balance between performance and fire resistance. Mineral wool core panels are chosen when fire safety and acoustic insulation are top priorities.<br><br>The right choice of sandwich panels is extremely important and connected with solving a number of technical problems, which due to our longstanding international experience are well known to us. The panels used by CT-TECHNOLOGIES are specially developed for cold storage or temperature controlled facilities and meet the main international standards. Besides the optimal choice of panels, CT-TECHNOLOGIES ensure the supply of all required materials for the installation of panels – of the correct type and in the required quantity. Additionally, factors such as budget, environmental considerations and long-term performance will also be taken into account.
  </p>

    <h2 id="sandwich-panel-technical-data">
      Sandwich Panel Technical Data
    </h2>

  <p>
    The technical specifications of sandwich panels can vary depending on the materials used. Some key data points include:
  </p>

  <ol class="list-number-bold">
    <li><b>Thermal Insulation:</b> R-value or U-value measures the thermal resistance or conductivity of the panels. Higher R-values or lower U-values indicate better insulation characteristics.
</li><li><b>Fire Resistance:</b> Panels can be rated for fire resistance, which is the capacity of element to maintain load bearing, integrity, and insulation properties during specific period of time, typically indicated in minutes. The specific rating will depend on the composition and fire-retardant properties of the materials used, primarily panel core.
</li><li><b>Load-Bearing Capacity:</b> Sandwich panels can have different load-bearing capacities depending on their core material and thickness.
</li><li><b>Panel Thickness:</b> Panels come in various thicknesses, which impact their insulation and structural properties.
</li><li><b>Weight:</b> The weight of sandwich panels can influence transport and handling during installation and also necessary support structure.
</li><li><b>Joining system:</b> Especially when used for low temperature application, rooms that are often washed down, facades and roof the joint design is very important.</li>
  </ol>

    <h2 id="how-to-install-sandwich-panels">
      How to Install Sandwich Panels
    </h2>

  <p>
    Installing sandwich panels can be a straightforward process requiring minimal work on site, making them an attractive option for various applications. Here is a simplified guide to applying sandwich panels:
  </p>

  <ol class="list-number-bold">
    <li><b>Surface Preparation: 
</b><br>Ensure that the surface where the panels will be installed is clean, level, and structurally sound. Any debris or irregularities can affect the integrity of the installation.</li><li><b>Measurement and Cutting: 
</b><br>Panels arrive on site typically in pre-determined lengths. Some cutting is required for openings, penetrations and Measure and cut the sandwich panels to the required size using appropriate tools. Be precise, as this step can significantly impact the final fit.</li><li><b>Fasteners: 
</b><br>Depending on the application, several type of fasteners can be used to fix panels to substructure and fix flashings to panels: self-drilling screws, self-tapping screws, rivets, bolts, or any combination of them.</li><li><b>Joint Sealing: 
</b><br>Seal the joints between the panels to prevent water and moisture infiltration and improve thermal efficiency. Special sealants designed for sandwich panels can be used for this purpose including fire retardant sealant and food safe sealants.</li><li><b>Finish and Cladding: 
</b><br>Standard finish for sandwich panels is polyester coating which comes in variety of colours. Other coatings include coating that do not face, high corrosion resistant coating etc. Exterior or interior sandwich panel sheets can be also be made out of special material like stainless steel, aluminium, copper etc. In addition to this, special final finishes are available like mirror finish, embossing, engraving, printing etc. In some circumstances, you may add a cladding material for protection and aesthetics, which could include paint, stucco, or other finishes.</li><li><b>Inspection and Quality Control:</b><br>Inspect the installed sandwich panels to ensure they are properly aligned, secured, and sealed.</li>
  </ol>

    <h2 id="advantages-of-using-sandwich-panels">
      Advantages of Using Sandwich Panels
    </h2>

  <p>
    Sandwich panels offer a multitude of advantages across various industries:
  </p>

  <ol class="list-number-bold">
    <li><b>High Insulation:</b> Excellent thermal insulation properties make them energy-efficient, reducing heating and cooling costs.
</li><li><b>Lightweight and Strong:</b> Despite their lightweight, sandwich panels are incredibly strong, making them ideal for applications where weight is a concern.
</li><li><b>Quick Installation:</b> The simplicity of installation saves time and labour costs.
</li><li><b>Versatility:</b> They can be used in a wide range of applications, from building construction to industrial equipment and transportation.
</li><li><b>Aesthetic Options:</b> Architectural sandwich panels come in various finishes, allowing for creative design choices.
</li><li><b>Environmental Benefits:</b> Many sandwich panels are recyclable, and their energy-efficient properties contribute to reduced carbon emissions.</li>
  </ol>

    <h2 id="conclusion">
      Conclusion
    </h2>

  <p>
    Sandwich panels have revolutionized construction and various other industries by offering a combination of strength, insulation, and versatility. Whether it's in building construction, refrigeration, or transportation, sandwich panels continue to prove their worth as a reliable and efficient construction material. Their technical data and ease of application make them a preferred choice for countless projects, offering both cost savings and performance benefits. As the demand for sustainable and energy-efficient building solutions continues to grow, sandwich panels are set to play a pivotal role in shaping the future of construction.
  </p>

  <p>
    We’d appreciate the opportunity to help you further, whether that be more information or a quote. Our team is with you each step of the way to ensure that your project is seamless and expertly executed.
  </p>

  <p class="align-center">
    Call CT-TECHNOLOGIES today to speak with our professional experts.
  </p>

  <p class="paragraph-contact-us align-center">
    <a href="https://www.ct-technologies.dk/contact">CONTACT US NOW</a>
  </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Comparing Conventional Warehouse Digitalization with Automated Warehouse (AS/RS) Investment</title>
        <author>
            <name>General Editors</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.ct-technologies.dk/comparing-conventional-warehouse-digitalization-with-automated-warehouse-asrs-investment/"/>
        <id>https://www.ct-technologies.dk/comparing-conventional-warehouse-digitalization-with-automated-warehouse-asrs-investment/</id>
            <category term="News"/>

        <updated>2023-11-08T11:45:44+07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    In the era of Industry 4.0, the transformation of warehouses has become imperative for businesses looking to streamline operations, enhance efficiency, and meet the demands of the ever-evolving market. Two prominent approaches to achieve this are conventional warehouse digitalization and investments in Automated Storage and&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                
  <p>
    In the era of Industry 4.0, the transformation of warehouses has become imperative for businesses looking to streamline operations, enhance efficiency, and meet the demands of the ever-evolving market. Two prominent approaches to achieve this are conventional warehouse digitalization and investments in Automated Storage and Retrieval Systems (AS/RS). CT-TECHNOLOGIES will explore and compare these two strategies, highlighting their advantages and drawbacks to help businesses make informed decisions about warehouse management.
  </p>

    <h2 id="a-conventional-warehouse-digitalization">
      A. Conventional Warehouse Digitalization
    </h2>

  <p>
    Conventional warehouse digitalization involves adopting digital technologies and software solutions to optimize warehouse operations. It typically includes the implementation of Warehouse Management Systems (WMS), barcode scanners, RFID systems, and other tools to enhance inventory tracking, order processing, and overall operational visibility.
  </p>

    <h3 id="advantages-of-conventional-warehouse-digitalization">
      Advantages of Conventional Warehouse Digitalization
    </h3>

  <ul>
    <li>Cost-Effective Entry Point: Conventional digitalization is often a more cost-effective starting point for small to medium-sized businesses looking to improve their warehouse operations.
</li><li>Flexibility: This approach allows for the gradual integration of digital technologies, making it easier for businesses to adapt to changes.
</li><li>Scalability: Businesses can scale their digitalization efforts as they grow, avoiding large upfront investments.
</li><li>Improved Visibility: WMS and tracking technologies provide better visibility into inventory, enabling more accurate demand forecasting and inventory management.</li>
  </ul>

    <h3 id="drawbacks-of-conventional-warehouse-digitalization">
      Drawbacks of Conventional Warehouse Digitalization
    </h3>

  <ul>
    <li>Limited Automation: This approach relies on manual labour for most tasks, limiting the degree of automation achievable.
</li><li>Efficiency Gains Are Limited: While digitalization can enhance certain aspects of warehouse operations, it may not lead to significant efficiency gains compared to AS/RS.</li>
  </ul>

    <h3 id="conventional-rack-storage-systems">
      Conventional Rack Storage Systems
    </h3>

    <h4 id="a-selective-pallet-racking-and-mobile-pallet-rack">
      a. Selective Pallet Racking and Mobile Pallet Rack
    </h4>

  <p>
    Advantage: High (100%) Selectivity, Area Utilization: 40% Storage, 60% Gangway.<br>High Stock Keeping Unit (SKU), Suitable for Distribution Center ( DC ) Warehouse, Raw Material (RM) Warehouse.
  </p>

    <figure class="post-hidden-item post__image post__image--center">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/wh1.jpg" height="798" width="1962" alt="Selective Pallet Racking and Mobile Pallet Rack"  sizes="100vw" srcset="https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/responsive/wh1-xs.jpg 300w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/responsive/wh1-sm.jpg 480w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/responsive/wh1-md.jpg 768w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/responsive/wh1-lg.jpg 1024w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/responsive/wh1-xl.jpg 1360w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/responsive/wh1-2xl.jpg 1600w">
      
    </figure>

    <h4 id="b-double-deep-pallet-rack">
      b. Double Deep Pallet Rack
    </h4>

  <p>
    Advantage: Density is better than Selective Pallet Racking (SPR), Area Utilization: 60% Storage, 40% Gangway.<br>Mid SKU, Suitable for DC Warehouse, third-party logistics (3PL).
  </p>

    <figure class="post-hidden-item post__image post__image--center">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/wh2.jpg" height="522" width="1305" alt="Double Deep Pallet Rack"  sizes="100vw" srcset="https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/responsive/wh2-xs.jpg 300w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/responsive/wh2-sm.jpg 480w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/responsive/wh2-md.jpg 768w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/responsive/wh2-lg.jpg 1024w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/responsive/wh2-xl.jpg 1360w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/responsive/wh2-2xl.jpg 1600w">
      
    </figure>

    <h4 id="c-drivein-amp-shuttle-rack">
      c. DRIVE-IN &amp; Shuttle Rack
    </h4>

  <p>
    Advantage: High Density, Area Utilization: 70% Storage, 30% Gangway.<br>Low SKU, Suitable for Factory Warehouse (Raw Material &amp; Finished Goods).
  </p>

    <figure class="post-hidden-item post__image post__image--center">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/wh3.jpg" height="577" width="1355" alt="DRIVE-IN & Shuttle Rack"  sizes="100vw" srcset="https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/responsive/wh3-xs.jpg 300w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/responsive/wh3-sm.jpg 480w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/responsive/wh3-md.jpg 768w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/responsive/wh3-lg.jpg 1024w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/responsive/wh3-xl.jpg 1360w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/responsive/wh3-2xl.jpg 1600w">
      
    </figure>

    <h4 id="d-multitier-longspan-shelving">
      d. Multi-Tier Longspan Shelving
    </h4>

  <p>
    Boxes/Pcs Picking<br>High SKU, Suitable for Retail DC Warehouse, Archive Warehouse Storage Services, Small Spare Parts
  </p>

    <figure class="post-hidden-item post__image post__image--center">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/wh4.jpg" height="577" width="1355" alt="Multi-Tier Longspan Shelving"  sizes="100vw" srcset="https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/responsive/wh4-xs.jpg 300w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/responsive/wh4-sm.jpg 480w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/responsive/wh4-md.jpg 768w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/responsive/wh4-lg.jpg 1024w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/responsive/wh4-xl.jpg 1360w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/responsive/wh4-2xl.jpg 1600w">
      
    </figure>

    <h3 id="conventional-warehouse-optimization-through-digitalization-warehouse-management-system">
      Conventional Warehouse Optimization Through Digitalization Warehouse Management System
    </h3>

    <figure class="post__image post__image--center">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/Picture1B.png" height="472" width="945" alt=""  sizes="100vw" srcset="https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/responsive/Picture1B-xs.png 300w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/responsive/Picture1B-sm.png 480w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/responsive/Picture1B-md.png 768w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/responsive/Picture1B-lg.png 1024w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/responsive/Picture1B-xl.png 1360w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/responsive/Picture1B-2xl.png 1600w">
      
    </figure>

    <figure class="post__image post__image--center">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/Picture2B.png" height="472" width="945" alt=""  sizes="100vw" srcset="https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/responsive/Picture2B-xs.png 300w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/responsive/Picture2B-sm.png 480w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/responsive/Picture2B-md.png 768w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/responsive/Picture2B-lg.png 1024w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/responsive/Picture2B-xl.png 1360w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/responsive/Picture2B-2xl.png 1600w">
      
    </figure>

    <h2 id="b-automated-warehouse-asrs-investment">
      B. Automated Warehouse (AS/RS) Investment
    </h2>

  <p>
    Automated Warehouses, equipped with Automated Storage and Retrieval Systems (AS/RS), are the epitome of warehouse automation. AS/RS systems is a mechanical system that automates the process of storing and retrieving goods from storage shelves using devices such as Stacker Cranes, Conveyors and Control Devices (WMS, WCS &amp; PLC). AS/RS helps increase efficiency, accuracy and speed in managing inventory and the picking process.
  </p>

    <h3 id="advantages-of-automated-warehouse-asrs-investment">
      Advantages of Automated Warehouse (AS/RS) Investment
    </h3>

  <ul>
    <li>High Efficiency: AS/RS systems significantly reduce labour requirements and enable 24/7 operation, resulting in higher efficiency and productivity.
</li><li>Accuracy and Precision: Automation reduces human error, leading to more accurate inventory management and order fulfilment.
</li><li>Space Optimization: AS/RS systems are designed to maximize vertical space utilization, reducing the need for extensive warehouse footprints.
</li><li>Scalability: Automated warehouses can be easily scaled to accommodate increased demand without proportionately increasing labour costs.</li>
  </ul>

    <h3 id="drawbacks-of-automated-warehouse-asrs-investment">
      Drawbacks of Automated Warehouse (AS/RS) Investment
    </h3>

  <ul>
    <li>High Initial Investment: Implementing AS/RS systems involves substantial upfront costs, which can be a barrier for smaller businesses.
</li><li>Complexity: Maintaining and troubleshooting complex AS/RS systems requires specialized skills and knowledge.
</li><li>Limited Flexibility: Once an AS/RS system is in place, making changes or adaptations can be challenging and costly</li>
  </ul>

    <h3 id="automatic-storage-and-retrieval-system">
      Automatic Storage and Retrieval System
    </h3>

    <h4 id="a-freestanding-asrs-cold-storage">
      a. Freestanding ASRS Cold Storage
    </h4>

    <figure class="post__image post__image--center">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/Picture3.jpg" height="419" width="1430" alt="Freestanding ASRS Cold Storage"  sizes="100vw" srcset="https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/responsive/Picture3-xs.jpg 300w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/responsive/Picture3-sm.jpg 480w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/responsive/Picture3-md.jpg 768w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/responsive/Picture3-lg.jpg 1024w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/responsive/Picture3-xl.jpg 1360w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/responsive/Picture3-2xl.jpg 1600w">
      
    </figure>

    <h4 id="b-rack-supported-building-rack-clad-asrs">
      b. Rack Supported Building (Rack Clad) ASRS
    </h4>

    <figure class="post__image post__image--center">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/Picture4.jpg" height="649" width="866" alt="Rack Supported Building (Rack Clad) ASRS"  sizes="100vw" srcset="https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/responsive/Picture4-xs.jpg 300w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/responsive/Picture4-sm.jpg 480w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/responsive/Picture4-md.jpg 768w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/responsive/Picture4-lg.jpg 1024w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/responsive/Picture4-xl.jpg 1360w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/responsive/Picture4-2xl.jpg 1600w">
      
    </figure>

    <h4 id="c-rack-supported-building-rack-clad-asrs-cold-storage">
      c. Rack Supported Building (Rack Clad) ASRS Cold Storage
    </h4>

    <figure class="post__image post__image--center">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/Picture5.jpg" height="399" width="1430" alt="Rack Supported Building (Rack Clad) ASRS Cold Storage"  sizes="100vw" srcset="https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/responsive/Picture5-xs.jpg 300w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/responsive/Picture5-sm.jpg 480w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/responsive/Picture5-md.jpg 768w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/responsive/Picture5-lg.jpg 1024w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/responsive/Picture5-xl.jpg 1360w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/26/responsive/Picture5-2xl.jpg 1600w">
      
    </figure>

    <h2 id="c-choosing-the-right-approach">
      C. Choosing the Right Approach
    </h2>

  <p>
    The choice between conventional warehouse digitalization and AS/RS investment depends on various factors, including a company's size, budget, and long-term goals.
<br>
<br>For small and medium-sized enterprises (SMEs) with limited budgets and gradual growth plans, conventional warehouse digitalization may be the more practical choice. It allows for incremental improvements without the need for massive capital investments.
<br>
<br>In contrast, large enterprises with high order volumes and a strong need for efficiency and accuracy may find AS/RS investment more appealing. The initial cost is offset by long-term savings through reduced labour and operational expenses.
<br>
<br>Due to the significant efficiency in energy and labour costs, the Annual Cost for ASRS is lower compared to Conventional Warehouse Digitalization, but the initial investment value for ASRS is relatively very high.
<br>
<br>An ROI (Return On Investment) evaluation is needed, namely how long it will take to get back the initial investment in ASRS through operational cost savings (reduction in labour) and efficiency (savings in energy use). The faster we can achieve ROI, the more profitable this ASRS investment will be.
<br>
<br>In conclusion, both conventional warehouse digitalization and AS/RS investment have their merits and drawbacks. Businesses should carefully evaluate their specific needs, budget constraints, and growth expectations when deciding which strategy to pursue. Ultimately, the right choice can lead to improved warehouse operations and a competitive edge in the evolving marketplace.
  </p>

  <p>
    We’d appreciate the opportunity to help you further, whether that be more information or a quote. Our team is with you each step of the way to ensure that your project is seamless and expertly executed.
  </p>

  <p class="align-center">
    Call CT-TECHNOLOGIES today to speak with our professional experts.
  </p>

  <p class="align-center">
    <a href="https://wa.me/6281287811053" target="_blank" class="" data-link-popup-id="1696917301003">Chat with us</a>
  </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Implementation of GCCA Study Tour to Indonesia</title>
        <author>
            <name>General Editors</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.ct-technologies.dk/implementation-of-gcca-study-tour-to-indonesia/"/>
        <id>https://www.ct-technologies.dk/implementation-of-gcca-study-tour-to-indonesia/</id>
            <category term="News"/>

        <updated>2023-11-08T11:44:14+07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Implementation of GCCA Study Tour to Indonesia, 8 – 9 May 2023 Undertaken with good preparation supported by cold chain industry stakeholders, the GCCA study tour which brought participants from Thailand, Cambodia, Philippines and Vietnam, began with a visit to one of the container ports&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                
    <blockquote class="blockquote">
      Implementation of GCCA Study Tour to Indonesia, 8 – 9 May 2023
    </blockquote>

    <figure class="post__image post__image--center">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/21/logo-ARPI.png" height="117" width="117" alt=""  sizes="100vw" srcset="https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/21/responsive/logo-ARPI-xs.png 300w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/21/responsive/logo-ARPI-sm.png 480w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/21/responsive/logo-ARPI-md.png 768w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/21/responsive/logo-ARPI-lg.png 1024w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/21/responsive/logo-ARPI-xl.png 1360w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/21/responsive/logo-ARPI-2xl.png 1600w">
      
    </figure>

  <p>
    Undertaken with good preparation supported by cold chain industry stakeholders, the GCCA study tour which brought participants from Thailand, Cambodia, Philippines and Vietnam, began with a visit to one of the container ports which was facilitated with the most plug-ins (990 pieces). and best for refrigerated reefer containers (New Priok Container Terminal one). Installation work on the construction of a 4-floor refrigerated distribution centre provided by PT. Sinar Primera (APP Sinar Mas group) became the main attraction for the participants. ASRS system (automation) cold chain storage PT. Indomaguro in Muara Baru and ASRS storage 6 levels (completed) adjoining the restaurant completed the study visit on the first day. The ASRS system is of concern to participants in implementing it in their respective countries and so will Indonesia in the future. CT Technologies explained the details on the second day before moving on to the next visit.
  </p>

  <p>
    The national leading 3 PL industry, MGM Bosco, which is currently preparing for the 4 PL industry, provides information on how the 3 PL industry will look in the future, which is equipped with an updated digitization system with attention to the speed of service and accuracy of delivery with product temperature information in real-time. The Condensing Unit assembly workshop (Bitzer brand CDU), as the heart of the cold storage refrigeration machine, the participants saw the assembly process which has already been manufactured in Indonesia (Bitzer Compressor Indonesia). The second day's visit ended with seeing the fabrication work on making refrigerated containers to be installed on transport vehicles (trucks and mini-vans) as well as portable-mobile storage that has TKDN certificates above 50% (Delima Mandiri).
  </p>

  <p>
    Supermarkets which are facilitated with product cold storage and delivery systems are also the focus of their study tour. Ranch Market explains in detail how to maintain the appropriate product temperature so that the products they sell have a premium price. Furthermore PT. Alpine Cool Utama explains the process of making insulation panels with an automated system (continuous line) that is reliable and has been able to export its products to several Asian countries.
  </p>

  <p>
    The Bali area is also reviewed, especially how to cultivate vegetables and fruit using hydroponic technology. The quality of the products produced, the packaging process in the packing house area and the delivery process to cold storage. Plaga Farm as a manager has been able to start exporting its products to consumer countries with good planning. This is an opportunity for the future. Meanwhile, Lotus Food Services, which is a distribution centre for imported and local food and beverages, can facilitate properly refrigerated storage and delivery. Brand Thermoking in cold product delivery, explained in detail by PT. Thermo Asri Makmur. The results of the post-evaluation of the implementation of the study tour with visits to the industries mentioned above received an average rating of 8.5 from a score level of 1 – 10 (a score of 10 is very, very satisfied).
  </p>

  <p>
    Source: <a href="http://arpionline.org/pelaksanaan-study-tour-gcca-ke-indonesia/" target="_blank">Pelaksanaan Study Tour GCCA ke Indonesia – ARPIonline</a>
  </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>“This is a big development, as at the moment there are no facilities”</title>
        <author>
            <name>General Editors</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.ct-technologies.dk/this-is-a-big-development-as-at-the-moment-there-are-no-facilities/"/>
        <id>https://www.ct-technologies.dk/this-is-a-big-development-as-at-the-moment-there-are-no-facilities/</id>
            <category term="News"/>

        <updated>2023-11-08T11:44:51+07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    CT Technologies is a cold chain solution provider founded more than 30 years ago with a vision to design and build sustainable facilities for food preservation and processing that are energy-saving and at the same time up to the highest standards in terms of hygiene&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                
  <p>
    CT Technologies is a cold chain solution provider founded more than 30 years ago with a vision to design and build sustainable facilities for food preservation and processing that are energy-saving and at the same time up to the highest standards in terms of hygiene and production.
<br>
<br>CT Technologies was founded in 1989 in Denmark where their head office is and they have their operational office in Bosnia and Herzegovina, an office in Indonesia, one in Philippines, one in Benin and in Ghana.&nbsp;<br>
  </p>

    <figure class="post__image post__image--center">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/19/Picture1.png" height="351" width="468" alt=""  sizes="100vw" srcset="https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/19/responsive/Picture1-xs.png 300w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/19/responsive/Picture1-sm.png 480w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/19/responsive/Picture1-md.png 768w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/19/responsive/Picture1-lg.png 1024w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/19/responsive/Picture1-xl.png 1360w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/19/responsive/Picture1-2xl.png 1600w">
      
    </figure>

  <p>
    The company is currently active in West Africa, in Benin where they are building a temperature-controlled facility at the Cotonou airport. All of Benin’s fresh produce exports will be stored in this warehouse while awaiting the planes for shipment. The facility will also be used to store imports of meat, chicken and pharmaceuticals before distribution.
<br>
<br>“This is a big development, as at the moment there are no facilities,” explains Roudy Akiki, CCO for Africa at CT-Technologies. “We are also building smaller modules for a client to enable him to expand his business from dry product to perishables.”
<br>
<br>CT-Technologies has just delivered facilities in Ghana and Nigeria which will be used for frozen meat and chicken, and they are looking at providing more cooling facilities for fresh produce in these countries.
<br>
<br>In East Africa the company has built a temperature-controlled airport facility in Burundi which will store fresh products such as pineapples and mango before they are exported; but will also receive the imported frozen goods and pharma products.
<br>
<br>“These facilities are designed and built by our company, we have also installed warehouse management systems to scan all products in and out, and the produce can be tracked back to source. We are also first to introduce Quad Core in TEMA Ghana, a technology that will allow using thinner panels for better performance keeping the temperature inside cold and contribute in reducing the electricity bills; We are one of very few companies who use Ammonia refrigeration system of 0 GWP in Africa to reduce as much as possible the impact on the environment.”
<br>
<br>In many African countries it is a real challenge to keep the cold chain intact, most fresh produce is trucked around in normal trucks with no cooling and around 50% of product is lost due to this.
<br>
<br>“Our projects in Burundi and Benin are financed by the World Bank, the idea is to develop the cold chain by installing smaller facilities throughout the countries to complete the cold chain. It is important that produce is kept at a controlled temperature from when it leaves the farms,” said Roudy.
<br>
<br>“We are receiving interest from other countries such as Egypt, Morocco, Senegal and Kenya all of whom are trying to improve their cold chains. Many African countries have a high rate of unemployment in younger people and many leave the farms to look for work elsewhere, this kind of investment will create opportunities for younger people. It could motivate them to stay on the farm, produce and take ownership of their produce.”&nbsp;<br>
  </p>

  <p>
    Source:&nbsp;<a href="https://www.freshplaza.com/europe/article/9523972/this-is-a-big-development-as-at-the-moment-there-are-no-facilities/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener" class="">https://www.freshplaza.com/europe/article/9523972/this-is-a-big-development-as-at-the-moment-there-are-no-facilities/</a>&nbsp;
  </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>CT TECHNOLOGIES Participate in Africa Innovation Network Seminar</title>
        <author>
            <name>General Editors</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.ct-technologies.dk/ct-technologies-participate-in-africa-innovation-network-seminar/"/>
        <id>https://www.ct-technologies.dk/ct-technologies-participate-in-africa-innovation-network-seminar/</id>
            <category term="News"/>

        <updated>2023-11-08T11:43:36+07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Critical infrastructure in Africa - how to further strengthen the business opportunities in Africa! Monday 17 April 2023, Africa Innovation Network are delighted to also welcome, CEO, Mr. Carsten Thorsen from the Danish company CT-TECHNOLOGIES at our seminar “Critical Infrastructure in Africa, April 17th, 2023,&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                
    <blockquote class="blockquote">
      Critical infrastructure in Africa - how to further strengthen the business opportunities in Africa!
    </blockquote>

  <p>
    Monday 17 April 2023, Africa Innovation Network are delighted to also welcome, CEO, Mr. Carsten Thorsen from the Danish company CT-TECHNOLOGIES at our seminar “Critical Infrastructure in Africa, April 17th, 2023, in Copenhagen.
  </p>

  <p>
    About CT Technologies
<br>CT-TECHNOLOGIES specializes in the design and supply of materials and equipment for the insulation of Cold Stores and Food Processing Plants. The high-quality service they provide is based on the specific demands of the clients. With 30 years of international experience, CT-TECHNOLOGIES have built up the unique knowledge and expertise that is required to execute almost any type of temperature / hygienically controlled facility within Food Storage, Fish Processing, Meat Processing, Vegetable and Fruit Processing, the Dairy and Ice-Cream Industry, as well as Ripening Rooms, Controlled Atmosphere Rooms, etc.&nbsp;<br>
  </p>

    <figure class="post__image post__image--center">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/18/Picture1.jpg" height="348" width="347" alt=""  sizes="100vw" srcset="https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/18/responsive/Picture1-xs.jpg 300w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/18/responsive/Picture1-sm.jpg 480w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/18/responsive/Picture1-md.jpg 768w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/18/responsive/Picture1-lg.jpg 1024w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/18/responsive/Picture1-xl.jpg 1360w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/18/responsive/Picture1-2xl.jpg 1600w">
      
    </figure>

  <p>
    Source: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/africa-innovation-network_business-africa-partnerships-activity-7054040434573991936-9npD" target="_blank">https://www.linkedin.com/posts/africa-innovation-network_business-africa-partnerships-activity-7054040434573991936-9npD</a>&nbsp;
  </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>CT TECHNOLOGIES Participate to Trade Council of Denmark in Sub-Saharan Africa Seminar in Ghana</title>
        <author>
            <name>General Editors</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.ct-technologies.dk/ct-technologies-participate-to-trade-council-of-denmark-in-sub-saharan-africa-seminar-in-ghana/"/>
        <id>https://www.ct-technologies.dk/ct-technologies-participate-to-trade-council-of-denmark-in-sub-saharan-africa-seminar-in-ghana/</id>
            <category term="News"/>

        <updated>2023-11-08T11:43:52+07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Turning food loss into value through partnerships! Saturday 11 March 2023, the Embassy of Denmark in Ghana arranged a seminar on Food Loss as part of its contribution to attaining UN SDG # 12.3, which seeks to increase resource efficiency and halve global per capita&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                
    <blockquote class="blockquote">
      Turning food loss into value through partnerships!
    </blockquote>

  <p>
    Saturday 11 March 2023, the Embassy of Denmark in Ghana arranged a seminar on Food Loss as part of its contribution to attaining UN SDG # 12.3, which seeks to increase resource efficiency and halve global per capita food waste.
<br>
<br>The hybrid event brought together stakeholders from the private sector, agro-producers and farmers, policy makers and NGO’s in both Ghana and Denmark. The seminar was a follow-up on a feasibility study report the Embassy launched in 2022 on cold chain solutions and business opportunities in Ghana. Yesterday provided an opportunity for the Danish companies <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/danfoss/" target="_blank">Danfoss </a>and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/ct-technologies/" target="_blank">CT-TECHNOLOGIES</a> to share concrete examples of how to combat food loss through partnerships and cold chain solutions.
<br>
<br>It is currently estimated that 50% of fruits, 40% of vegetables and 20% of tuber crops are lost annually along the food value chain in Ghana. As CEO of <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/freezelink/" target="_blank">FreezeLink</a> described it: “In Denmark, half of your salary goes to taxes. This pays for education, hospitals, infrastructure and more. And Danes are happy to pay their taxes. Now imagine, as Ghanaians, a situation where half of your salary is taken and just lost. This is what happens to our farmers daily.”
<br>
<br>The Embassy hopes to inspire future Danish-Ghanaian commercial partnerships to combat food loss. Thanks to <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/food-nation-denmark/" target="_blank">Food Nation Denmark</a>, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/solidaridad-network/" target="_blank">Solidaridad Network</a> and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/dmdp-danida/" target="_blank">Danida Green Business Partnerships / Danida Market Development Partnerships</a> for your contributions!&nbsp;
  </p>

    <figure class="post__image post__image--center">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/17/Picture1-2.jpg" height="369" width="601" alt=""  sizes="100vw" srcset="https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/17/responsive/Picture1-2-xs.jpg 300w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/17/responsive/Picture1-2-sm.jpg 480w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/17/responsive/Picture1-2-md.jpg 768w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/17/responsive/Picture1-2-lg.jpg 1024w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/17/responsive/Picture1-2-xl.jpg 1360w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/17/responsive/Picture1-2-2xl.jpg 1600w">
      
    </figure>

  <p>
    Source : <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/tradecouncilofdenmarkssa_turning-food-loss-into-value-through-partnerships-activity-7039952233953673216-qEd7?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=member_desktop" target="_blank">https://www.linkedin.com/posts/tradecouncilofdenmarkssa_turning-food-loss-into-value-through-partnerships-activity-7039952233953673216-qEd7?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=member_desktop</a>
  </p>

  <p>
    
  </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>WLFO Signs Contracts for Projects in Benin and Burundi</title>
        <author>
            <name>General Editors</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.ct-technologies.dk/wlfo-signs-contracts-for-projects-in-benin-and-burundi/"/>
        <id>https://www.ct-technologies.dk/wlfo-signs-contracts-for-projects-in-benin-and-burundi/</id>
            <category term="News"/>

        <updated>2023-11-08T11:45:06+07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    In January 2022, WFLO signed contracts with GCCA member LixCap to provide technical support to ensure the safe and commercially viable operation of temperature-controlled facilities in Benin and Burundi. The team is focused on delivering a concept design for state-funded cold chain facilities and design&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                
    <figure class="post__image post__image--center">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/20/logo-GCCA.png" height="59" width="315" alt=""  sizes="100vw" srcset="https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/20/responsive/logo-GCCA-xs.png 300w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/20/responsive/logo-GCCA-sm.png 480w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/20/responsive/logo-GCCA-md.png 768w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/20/responsive/logo-GCCA-lg.png 1024w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/20/responsive/logo-GCCA-xl.png 1360w ,https://www.ct-technologies.dk/media/posts/20/responsive/logo-GCCA-2xl.png 1600w">
      
    </figure>

  <p>
    In January 2022, WFLO signed contracts with GCCA member LixCap to provide technical support to ensure the safe and commercially viable operation of temperature-controlled facilities in Benin and Burundi. The team is focused on delivering a concept design for state-funded cold chain facilities and design and tender documentation for the facilities.
  </p>

  <p>
    GCCA was requested by the governments in both countries to develop preliminary designs for the projects. They will be supported by GCCA technical experts Richard Dowdell and Manuel Cabrera Kabana.
<br>
  </p>

  <p>
    CEBA member CT-Technologies was awarded the contract to build the cold storage facility in the airport of Bujumbura, Burundi, in December 2021. In Benin, the client PACOFIDE will soon launch a tender process for the conditioning facility in the Grand Nokoué wholesale market. This tender process directly follows the successful cold chain rapid response and strategy developed by the consortium.
<br>
  </p>

  <p>
    These World Bank-funded projects mark WFLO’s first two awards of 2022.&nbsp;<br>
  </p>

  <p>
    Source: <a href="https://www.gcca.org/news-announcements/wflo-signs-contracts-projects-benin-and-burundi/" target="_blank">WFLO signs contracts for projects in Benin and Burundi - Global Cold Chain Alliance (gcca.org)</a>
  </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>GLOBAL TRENDS IN CONSTRUCTING TEMPERATURE CONTROLLED</title>
        <author>
            <name>General Editors</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.ct-technologies.dk/global-trends-in-constructing-temperature-controlled/"/>
        <id>https://www.ct-technologies.dk/global-trends-in-constructing-temperature-controlled/</id>
            <category term="News"/>

        <updated>2023-11-08T11:42:04+07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    BUILDING AROUND THE WORLD Building Around The World Innovation in thermal building projects is happening at a rapid pace on almost every continent. Here is a snapshot of some of the trends in building high quality, food safety-focused, temperature-controlled environments in the Americas, Europe, South&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                
    <blockquote class="blockquote">
      BUILDING AROUND THE WORLD
    </blockquote>

  <p>
    <b>Building Around The World
</b><br>
<br> Innovation in thermal building projects is happening at a rapid pace on almost every continent. Here is a snapshot of some of the trends in building high quality, food safety-focused, temperature-controlled environments in the Americas, Europe, South East Asia, and Africa.
<br>
<br><b>Hot in Canada
</b><br>
<br>“It’s a hot climate these days in Canada, with lots of activity and growth in food processing and manufacturing,” notes Marko Dzeletovich, P. Eng, President of Coldbox Builders. “A healthy economy, changes in consumer preferences and ways of purchasing food, meal kit companies becoming more common – all of these factors have an impact on the decisions that are made in building cold storage and processing facilities.” Dzeletovich says at this moment, the number one trend in Canada in innovative thermal building projects is end users requesting turnkey solutions and a guaranteed completion date. “It’s a sign of the business climate, schedule is very important.” He adds that there is great demand from customers to find a single cold storage and processing facility specialist to pull it all together. “It helps to speed up the schedule. There are so many technological and system options to choose from, and so little time for planning right now, end users need someone with the expertise to provide solutions, so they can get their facility into the market as fast as possible.” Another trend Dzeletovich points to is the increase in cross-border partnerships.
<br>“I’m seeing an increase in American companies with local clients needing a Canadian design-build partner to facilitate U.S. client growth in Canada.” Automation is a big topic these days, according to Dzeletovich. “Semi or fully automated facilities are starting to go up and operators are exploring their options and running models to see how automation can benefit their business.” When weighing whether to go with an automated facility, one has to determine how many pallets are going through the PRW against other costs, Dzeletovich explains. “Automation systems are highly flexible and 3PLs want flexibility. Automation gives you higher density, greater height, and a smaller footprint but if you build conventionally and sprawl out, you can’t take advantage of that space at a later time. Also, automated facilities can operate at night, in the dark, staging product. A warehouseman sitting idle costs money.” Dzeletovich points out that while the cost of labor and shortage of workers in nonautomated controlled-environment buildings continues to be an issue, there’s no shortage of workers interested in technology and programming. “There are plenty of folks who would like to work in a fully automated space. Augmenting and maintaining automated systems is really interesting.” But one of the main drivers in weighing the benefits of automation in Canada, says Dzeletovich, is whether there’s developed land available. “It’s difficult to get developers to agree to purpose-built facilities like automated temperature-controlled buildings,” Dzeletovich says. “Developers are looking out 20 plus years and consider how this specialized building can be repurposed. Just as 3PLs want flexibility to accommodate future clients, land developers want a building that is as flexible as possible for their future tenant.” Dzeletovich acknowledges it impacts the move to automation to some degree.
<br>
<br><b>Pharma in the USA
</b><br>
<br>The first fully automated temperature-controlled facility opened in the United States in 2018. “Regarding automation, it’s been a shot in the arm for the PRW industry and garnering a lot of attention. However, we’re not seeing dramatic changes yet, the ball is slowly moving down the field,” says Jake Stefan, President of ARCO Design/Build BTS, Inc. “I can tell you that automation in the cold world in the United States has a bigger foothold in facilities designed around a specific product(s) – for example facilities that are dedicated to manufacturing plants,” Stefan notes. “Investment is still very high on automated material handling systems so if the products being stored use similar pallet dimensions and can be handled on the sameASRS, mole system or any other automation oriented retrieval system, it’s much easier for the operator to stomach.” There is one cold storage market that is growing by leaps and bounds says Stefan, and that is specialty pharmaceuticals, which all tend to be temperature controlled.
<br>“The specialty pharma, or cold storage segment, is one of the fastest growing in the pharmaceutical industry. Unfortunately, even though I like it growing quickly, I’m not sure specialty pharma is going to fill your warehouse,” Stefan warns. “Pill bottles are tiny and are stored by box or case, not pallet, so much of specialty pharma is stored within walk-in coolers rather than forklift drive-in coolers. We recently completed a pharmaceutical distribution facility with a large cooler by pharmaceutical standards, but, in the end, it was still only 3,000 square feet expandable to 6,000.” There are ways for a controlled environment facility to share space between pharma and other products, Stefan says, but because of the stringent requirements of the DEA and pharma manufacturers, the cold pharma has typically been stored in independent facilities versus comingled facilities with completely dedicated storage spaces. Stefan notes that he has been fielding questions from customers about one specific product related to the pharma world that can be stored in the same temperature-controlled facility as food. “A pill bottle measures a couple of inches but the frozen ice packs that go in the shipping containers take up a lot more space, have to be temperature controlled during storage, and have no related security risks,” Stefan says. “I can see a pharma distributor partnering with a facility that can blast freeze and store pallets of ice packs, allowing the distributor to receive a pallet or two as needed.” One area of growth for Stefan’s companyhas been in designing and building cleanrooms for pharma – a controlled environment that has a low level of tolerance for pollutants such as dust, vapors, and often times humidity, for manufacturing or scientific research. “Although there are different rules and regulations for cold cleanrooms versus cold food storage, the concept of building sanitary, air, and water tight storage is the same. The techniques and materials used in the construction of these cleanrooms are very similar to those used in cold storage,” Stefan explains. “So our expertise, technical awareness, and attention to detail from building cold storage has been a big factor in our success in the pharma world.” Any other construction trend on Stefan’s mind? “Yes, jointless floor systems! They have such great value, I can’t understand why they haven’t become the standard – I’ve done some for PRWs but never done one yet for a food distribution facility.”
<br>
<br><b>Efficiencies in Mexico
</b><br>
<br>Alfredo Garza, General Director, Infrisa Mexico, couldn’t agree more with Stefan. “The trend for us is to install concrete floors without joints – they require less maintenance, they increase operational efficiencies, they’re more sanitary, they’re easier on forklifts and their operators because there are no bumps, and they’re flatter, which makes them more secure when using high racks.” Garza says there are also trends in the kind of insulation being used for thermal building projects. “The type of foam insulation we’re using today has revolutionized operating systems in Mexico and efficiencies in cold storage are significantly greater.” Garza says the insulation is a foam PIR (Polyisocyanurate) that has a lot of structural advantages because it is quite rigid and strong which translates into less panel breakage and shrinking during construction. The trends in wall design are focused on the type of materials being used and those materials, as well as the paint that will be used, are selected based on the type of product being stored and the chemicals used to clean the walls and how aggressively those chemicals will be used. “All these elements impact the way you design and specify panels so you really have to know your client and their products,” Garza points out. Doors also are among the new technologies that are creating better and safer temperature-controlled facilities, Garza notes. “Today, there are so many doors to choose from that make internal operations more efficient. You have to sit down with your client and explain the different technologies that are available in the market based on the nature of the client’s operation.” Garza says that because of climate change and the risk to the environment that ammonia poses, the type of refrigerants now used in temperature-controlled warehouses in Mexico are more efficient and safer. “We’re recommending systems that use a mix of refrigerant ammonia and glycol and this reduces kilos of ammonia from the system.” “Overall, there’s a lot of need for coldstorage construction in Mexico,” Garza points out. “We have a very low percentage of square meters of temperature controlled storage for the population, and the facilities we do have are too spread out creating long distances for refrigerated transportation to travel.”
<br>
<br><b>Going High in the UK
</b><br>
<br>“One of the biggest trends impacting cold storage in the United Kingdom is younger consumers buying smaller quantities of groceries more often and not going to large supermarkets,” says Tony Wall, Managing Director of ISD Solutions, the largest temperature-controlled facility builder in the United Kingdom. “With this trend, we’re seeing the emergence of convenience stores and the decline of big box stores.” Wall adds that the other major demographic trend – younger consumers shopping for groceries online – is having a massive impact at every level of the food supply
<br>chain. “The frozen food market is growing immensely in the United Kingdom as it is elsewhere in Europe. Every store is addingmore frozen aisles, with ambient temperature discount stores looking to get into the frozen food market.”Wall says that the United Kingdom’s economy has a 30 to 35 percent cold storage requirement and with the huge upsurge in demand for frozen food, his company has never been so busy building cold storage.
<br>And what they’re building are automated high bay (high rise) temperature-controlled facilities. “Now that there is a 20-year track record since the first high bay was built in Belgium, when clients are looking at a new project with high volume, they look at high bay first.” Wall says the industry has changed a great deal since the first high bay facilities came into the market and has become very specialized. “Contractors like us used to manufacture and install ourselves, but now high bays are such expensive and technically challenging projects to build, contractors partner with manufacturers to provide a solution.” Wall says moving into new global markets depends not only on having good partners, but also on your company’s track record. “You can’t give high bay jobs to just any builder – it’s a huge load on the ground.” For ISD Solutions, its partnership has been with Kingspan, one of Europe’s leading construction product manufacturers – ISD Solutions is its largest customer for temperature-controlled panels in Western Europe. Wall says, “With Kingspan being a global company, it allows us to work anywhere in the world. We just entered the Australian market with the completion of that country’s first high bay in 2017, and are fielding inquiries from the Middle East and Asia.”
<br>
<br><b>Growth in Africa and Southeast Asia
</b><br>
<br>Carsten Thorsen, CEO of CT-TECHNOLOGIES, a Danish company specializing in engineering climate-controlled facilities, says his company builds all over the world and is anticipating 20 percent growth annually in the coming years in demand for their services in Southeast Asia (SEA), and in Africa, particularly in Ghana and Nigeria. Thorsen says in Africa, where the company has been operating for 15 years, they supply more projects on a turnkey basis, providing everything from floor insulation, steel structure, refrigeration equipment, panels, and doors. In building temperaturecontrolled facilities in SEA over the past 30 years, he says they are more likely to provide sandwich panels, floor insulation, and doors. “While our African customers are more interested in purchasing the entire solution from one company, another big difference between the two regions is that in South East Asia, ASRS and high-rise warehouses are more prevalent whereas in Africa, the concept is still new and interest low.” Thorsen adds that the growth in high rise buildings and ASRS in Southeast Asia, estimated to grow by 12 percent per year, is driven by increasing labor costs, lack of space, and the improved efficiencies that the high rise ASRS buildings allow. “Energy efficiency is a very important aspect for many clients and with the rising energy prices in all the countries we work in, this is becoming increasingly critical.” To address energy efficiency, Thorsen says the company is focusing more and more on providing photovoltaic (solar) solutions for their cold store customers. He adds that the solar panels themselves have not changed much in recent years, but what has changed is the cost. “The prices are lower now than they were a few years ago, so that is also fueling interest in solar on the part of our SEA and African clients. Now the focus is on making the batteries, where excess energy is stored and used at night, cheaper. ” Thorsen said another trend is that fire resistance is coming more into focus in Southeast Asia, with customers asking for solutions that satisfy stricter requirements. It is also a high priority because of past fires that have resulted in loss of life.“In cold stores, we typically use PIR panels that are self-extinguishing and optimal in controlling smoke development, and temperature and fire penetration,” Thorson notes. “In other buildings with even higher priority on fire safety, such as high rise cold storage facilities, we use mineral wool panels as they are highly fire resistant and act as a fire barrier, slowing down fires and giving the responders more time to get the fire under control.” Another new technology that Thorsen says his company is starting to use, and which he believes will become more widespread in SEA, is active fire protection systems that reduce oxygen concentration levels, actively inhibiting fires from developing or spreading. “Unlike sprinkler-based fire protection, oxygen reduction prevents fires from starting in the first place.”
<br>
<br><i>Article written by Alexandra Walsh, published in September-October 2018 issue of COLD FACTS magazine</i>
  </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>